[Music]
foreign
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to try
sentence Tasker advanced level training
so this is our lesson 5 in terms of
advanced level training and it's a
lesson 20 in terms of overall price and
testoster automation Concepts
so in this lesson I'm gonna teach you a
very important concept called a recovery
scenarios
so please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos
thank you
okay so let us understand what is
recovery scenario
so recovery scenario it's an
instructions that tell Tosca what to do
in order to recover a test case that
might have failed while running a test
during final execution
so if recovery scenario is run
successfully Tasker will retry test case
according to the retry level set that
means if recovery scenario is
successfully run right then Tosca will
retry the test case according to the
retry level set
if recovery scenario fails then Tosca
will go to the next recovery scenario
available
and Recovery scenario can be added to
recovery scenario collection which can
be added anywhere within the test case
section so basically the retry level
whatever you set at the recovery
scenario level is at test case level
or you can set a test set test step
level or you can set a test step value
level that means
in case
the test case fails then the recovery
scenario will trigger
and then it can run your entire test
case again or it can run a particular
test step again or it can run a test
step value again so there are three
levels where you can basically set your
retry level
okay now let's jump onto the system and
see how can you create recovery
scenarios in Tosca
and then how can we use them in
automating our test cases
okay so this is my transientist task
16 right so if you see in the left side
under test case section there is an
exercise folder okay so all these
folders it comes along with the
um
TSU file that you have downloaded in
earlier session right in earlier session
what we did we have downloaded a TSU
file
um let me show you that okay we have
downloaded a TSC file
called
this one additional material right
additional material base dot TSU so this
once you download this you will get all
these predefined test cases okay so for
this you need to go to your recovery
scenarios under recovery scenarios you
will find login and logout okay so what
does this test case so this test case
simply logs in to the FIB
this uh demo webshop it performs login
activity and then
by entering the username and password
okay and then it logs out wait for again
login link and close the webshop so it's
simple login and logout functionality
that we are verifying as part of this
test case
okay so now I want to introduce a
recovery scenario for this test case
automated test case okay for that right
click and you need to select recovery
scenario collection create recovery
select scenario collection click on this
and under recovery scenario collection
create a recovery scenario so this is
your recovery scenario create recovery
scenario
okay
so under
recovery scenario I'm gonna add a
three modules okay first one is
I need to add
top menu
okay
and let me name this as
log out
and then
the next one is
again let's call the same top menu
one more time
and name this as
weight
until
login wait until logout logged out wait
until logged out okay
and then
standard I'm going to call a standard
um
module close browser okay
and then let's enter the values
so I want to perform log out
and then I want to wait for login right
to appear on the screen
so for that
I need to select visible
equal to true
you have to wait until it is visible so
select action mode as waiter
and here title of your window to be
closed is demo
so what I am doing here so I've created
One recovery scenario
for
this login logout test case why why I
have created recovery scenario for this
login logo test case let me explain
see when I am executing the automated
test case where I am actually
validating the functionality of login
and then log out right
so there for example if your browser
what if your browser
are your webshop is already logged in
if my webshop is already logged in if I
run this test case
then my test case is going to fail
because
it is not able to find out login link
because I already logged in
it finds out the logout but not the
login
but in this test case first you are
logging in right
so now I want to recover this kind of
kind of scenario basically this test
case needs to be recovered in case of
this kind of scenarios if if the browser
is logged in I want to log out
and then close the browser so that is
what the recovery scenario we introduced
here right logout so let's see here and
then here go to the properties click on
recovery scenario go to the properties
you need to select the recovery scenario
this retrieval level is at test case
level or test step level so I want to
select this as test case in case my test
case login logout test case actual test
case
fails then I'm asking to
re-trigger trigger I mean sorry I'm
asking to trigger this recovery scenario
and do some action and then re-run the
test case that's why retry level is test
case
okay
so here
let's save this
and then go to execution list because as
I told you earlier
the recovery scenarios cannot be
triggered when you run in the scratch
book so these recovery scenarios can be
invoked only when you run in the
execution list okay okay so before I run
the test case let us make sure the
recovery scenario in the settings okay
go to Project
and go to settings so you need to see
the recovery scenario settings okay that
is very important
under settings you need to go to t-box
so here t-box under t-box you will have
a recovery
so here on dialog failure or extraction
failure on verification failure okay so
I want to make them as recover so let's
select them as recover okay
okay
that's it so these two we need to make
sure that all the verifications
will make the match recover okay and
then close it
so now let's trigger this because
whenever I trigger this right your
webshop will be opened with already
logged in correct so now your test case
login test case should fail
correct
so let me see how did I map this here
okay let me just map it this the test
case again okay let's go back here let's
map this login test case to our
execution recovery scenario execution
list
okay so now let's run the scenario right
click and run your execution list
so when I run this
the webshop will be opened it is already
logged in it will not be able to see the
login and then recovery scenario should
trigger
see it triggered the recovery scenario
it logged out it closed the webshop and
then again it's open the webshop so that
means it's working our scenario is
working correctly basically the recovery
scenario got triggered okay
so
hope you all understand the concept of
recovery scenario okay so if you have
any queries uh leave your queries in the
comment box I'll try to respond to your
queries okay thank you
[Music]